{"test_questions": [[{"question": "SCD, TEF, UGH, ____, WKL", "opta": "CMN", "optb": "UJI", "optc": "VIJ", "optd": "IJT", "ans": "C", "explanation": "There are two alphabetical series here. The first series is with the first letters only: STUVW. The second series involves the remaining letters: CD, EF, GH, IJ, KL."}, {"question": "B2CD, _____, BCD4, B5CD, BC6D", "opta": "B2C2D", "optb": "BC3D", "optc": "B2C3D", "optd": "BCD7", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Because the letters are the same, concentrate on the number series, which is a simple 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 series, and follows each letter in order."}, {"question": "FAG, GAF, HAI, IAH, ____", "opta": "JAK", "optb": "HAL", "optc": "HAK", "optd": "JAI", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The middle letters are static, so concentrate on the first and third letters. The series involves an alphabetical order with a reversal of the letters. The first letters are in alphabetical order: F, G, H, I , J. The second and fourth segments are reversals of the first and third segments. The missing segment begins with a new letter."}, {"question": "ELFA, GLHA, ILJA, _____, MLNA", "opta": "OLPA", "optb": "KLMA", "optc": "LLMA", "optd": "KLLA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The second and forth letters in the series, L and A, are static. The first and third letters consist of an alphabetical order beginning with the letter E."}, {"question": "CMM, EOO, GQQ, _____, KUU", "opta": "GRR", "optb": "GSS", "optc": "ISS", "optd": "ITT", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The first letters are in alphabetical order with a letter skipped in between each segment: C, E, G, I, K. The second and third letters are repeated; they are also in order with a skipped letter: M, O, Q, S, U."}, {"question": "ZA5, Y4B, XC6, W3D, _____", "opta": "E7V", "optb": "V2E", "optc": "VE5", "optd": "VE7", "ans": "D", "explanation": "There are three series to look for here. The first letters are alphabetical in reverse: Z, Y, X, W, V. The second letters are in alphabetical order, beginning with A. The number series is as follows: 5, 4, 6, 3, 7."}, {"question": "QPO, NML, KJI, _____, EDC", "opta": "HGF", "optb": "CAB", "optc": "JKL", "optd": "GHI", "ans": "A", "explanation": "This series consists of letters in a reverse alphabetical order."}, {"question": "JAK, KBL, LCM, MDN, _____", "opta": "OEP", "optb": "NEO", "optc": "MEN", "optd": "PFQ", "ans": "B", "explanation": "This is an alternating series in alphabetical order. The middle letters follow the order ABCDE. The first and third letters are alphabetical beginning with J. The third letter is repeated as a first letter in each subsequent three-letter segment."}, {"question": "BCB, DED, FGF, HIH, ___", "opta": "JKJ", "optb": "HJH", "optc": "IJI", "optd": "JHJ", "ans": "A", "explanation": "This series consists of a simple alphabetical order with the first two letters of all segments: B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K. The third letter of each segment is a repetition of the first letter."}, {"question": "P5QR, P4QS, P3QT, _____, P1QV", "opta": "PQW", "optb": "PQV2", "optc": "P2QU", "optd": "PQ3U", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The first two letters, PQ, are static. The third letter is in alphabetical order, beginning with R. The number series is in descending order beginning with 5."}, {"question": "QAR, RAS, SAT, TAU, _____", "opta": "UAV", "optb": "UAT", "optc": "TAS", "optd": "TAT", "ans": "A", "explanation": "In this series, the third letter is repeated as the first letter of the next segment. The middle letter, A, remains static. The third letters are in alphabetical order, beginning with R."}, {"question": "DEF, DEF2, DE2F2, _____, D2E2F3", "opta": "DEF3", "optb": "D3EF3", "optc": "D2E3F", "optd": "D2E2F2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "In this series, the letters remain the same: DEF.\nThe subscript numbers follow this series:\n 111, 112, 122, 222, 223, 233, 333, ..."}]]}